Andrew Bigby

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

954-695-7745 | abigby@live.com | Port Saint Lucie, FL, United States

ABOUT ME – Primary Focus

I am a self-motivated and system for success oriented Senior Frontend Software Developer who not only focuses on writing clean, elegant and efficient code; creating scalable applications using a range of technologies and programming languages. Something that's unique about me is that I have a background in design, subsequently, I often contribute to User Experience discussions and User Interface design wireframing the development of low and high-fidelity mockups.

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University - FAU - 2013 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

TECHNICAL SKILLS

DEVELOPMENT: CSS3 | SASS | SCSS | HTML5 | Angular 17 | Angular Material | React.js | Next.js | JavaScript ES8 | TypeScript | RxJS | Node.js | Nest.js | Express.js | MongoDB | Mongoose | GraphQL | SQL | MySQL | NoSQL | Unit Testing | e2e Testing | Cypress | Jest | Python 3

DESIGN: Wireframes | Mockups | User Interface Design UI | User Experience Design UX | Single Page Applications SPA | Responsive Web Design | Mobile First | Micro-Frontend

QUALITATIVE: Oral Communication | Problem Solving | UI Design | UX Design | Web Technologies

TOOLS

VSCode | Git Version Control | Jira | Terminal | Git Bash | Angular CLI | Nest.js CLI | Chrome Dev Tools | GitLab | GitHub | Azure | Microsoft Visio | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator | Figma | Balsamiq | Postman | Webpack | Webpack Module Federation | SCRUM Agile

WORK PREFERENCE

Work Location: 100% Remote Preferred

Employment Types: Full-Time, Contract-Hire (C2H)

Industry Experiences: Telehealth, Telecom, eCommerce, Biotech, Healthcare, Fintech

Project Types: Green Field, Migration or Existing Project

WORK EXPERIENCE

HUD The Department of Housing and Urban Development (KForce Inc., Contract)

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER - REMOTE

LRS: Loan Review System (LRS) is the electronic platform for most Federal Housing Administration (FHA) Title II Single Family quality assurance review processes. The purpose of LRS is to perform FHA Single Family Title II mortgage reviews, test case loan reviews, various Title II post endorsement loan reviews, various Title II post endorsement loan reviews, Title II lender monitoring reviews, and Title II loan reviews reported by lenders due to instances of Fraud and misrepresentation or other material findings. LRS merges and unifies the loan review workload management functions and lender reporting functions into a single integrated application.

- Display data using interactive tables and different types of charts
- Integrated new features and perform code maintenance task in Angular

• Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

Environment: Angular 16, TypeScript, JavaScript, RxJS, Restful API, Jira, Git, CSS, Kanban, Cypress, Jest, e2e Testing

SEC - Securities & Exchange Commission (Arch Systems Inc., Contract)

OCT 2022 - FEB 2023

SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER - REMOTE

OIDS: A one-stop-shop application for business users to extract quantitative and qualitative data and generate risk-based analysis reports.

- Display data using interactive tables and different types of charts via Angular Material.
- Integrate new features that enable users to take advantage of predefined runtime configuration parameters based on refined User Stories; broken down in prioritized task in Azure.
- Integrate report generation features and capabilities (editing, bulk upload, report download scheduling, group reports etc.)
- Proficiently utilized Figma to create and review design mockups, wireframes, collaborating seamlessly with development teams.
 - Leveraged Figma's design-to-code features to facilitate the translation of visual designs into actual code
- Used Angular for creating SPA, interactive UI's
- Used git for version control
- Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

Environment: Angular 14, TypeScript, RxJS, Restful API, Jira, Git, Java, Java Spring Boot, CSS, Azure, SCRUM Agile

NEOGENOMICS LABORATORIES Inc.

DEC 2020 – AUG 2022

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - REMOTE

Cohort Builder Application: A cancer testing-and-research focused dashboard style web application. The application gives professional users the ability to get answers to complex questions related to precision oncology biomarker testing and treatment options. The application allows users to create precision oncology cohorts via drag and drop features which can then be saved and shared with approved colleagues in network. Cohorts provide various charted visuals (Geographic, Patient Demographic, Provider & Patient Data, Facility Data etc.) based on real-time data from selected dragged and dropped query options. Cohorts are both in graphical view and string formats.

- Integrated data filtering features and tools in Angular 12 to manage data used for FISH testing.
- Display data using interactive tables and different types of charts via Angular Material and HighCharts respectively.
- Integrated features that adhere to HIPPA standards
- Migrate, integrate new features and develop new projects based on refined User Stories; broken down in prioritized task in Azure.
- Reduced technical debt through refactoring code and transitioning to new 3rd party tools etc.
- Usability Testing.
- Participated in User Experience and User Interface Design discussions
- Proficiently utilized Figma to create and review design markups, collaborating seamlessly with development teams.
 - Leveraged Figma's design-to-code features to facilitate the translation of visual designs into actual code
- Used git for version control

Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

Environment: Angular 12, Angular Material, React.js, TypeScript, RxJS, MySQL, Snowflake, RESTful API, Figma, Azure, Git, Java, SASS, SCRUM Agile, Micro-Frontend

CLEARLY AGILE Inc.

NOV 2019 - DEC 2020

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - REMOTE

QRMS – Quality Review Management System: A web application that provides engagement management.

- Implement web application and development principles to build stable software.
- Create new features, functional and capabilities based on refined User Stories; broken down in prioritized task.
- Integrated complex conditional logic forms to solve or meet fundamental issues or needs in the business' line of service.
- Display and manage data using tables, autocompletes, tabs, grids, lists etc.
- Create new service endpoints using Nest.js
- Usability and Unit Tests
- Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.
- Used git for version control

Environment: Angular, Angular Material, RESTful API, Node.js, Nest.js, Jest, TypeScript, RxJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Git, C#, .NET, SASS, CSS, SCRUM Agile

VERIZON DATA SERVICES (Newt Global, Contract)

JAN 2017 - AUG 2019

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - TAMPA, FL

Nautilus: An inventory management application that provides industry standard data model for telecommunication devices, cell sites, cable networks and connections. New devices can be plugged in and discovered for use. Create services that support all layers (Physical, Logical)

- Migration project translating old specifications into new integration
- Created basic and advanced search components to filter data
- Sort and Manage results using Datatables
- Load records based on selected search result
- Integrated tools that interact with physical network devices etc.
- Used git for version control
- Worked with REST APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

IP Management Module: A unified IP Management Service dashboard application that manages a pool of IP address assignments across different regions.

- Translated mockups/wireframe using React.js workflows
- Identified web-based user interactions and developed highly responsive user interface components using React.js concepts
- Developed React.js re-usable and styled components
- Used React.js in the development of an IP management dashboard which allows engineers to generate management solutions for its IP listings across multiple regions. This was accomplished through using React.js to

implement CRUD operations; such as searching, assigning IPs, unassigning IPs, updating IPs and removing on several devices dynamically

- Participated in User Experience and User Interface Design discussions
- Used Microsoft Visio to create mockups and wireframes for new feature integration into the User Interface.
- Developed low and high-fidelity mockup
- Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

Environment: Angular, RESTful API, React.js, Microsoft Visio, Git, jQuery, Jira, Java, Java Spring Boot, CSS

HEALTH PLAN SERVICES Inc.

APR 2016 - OCT 2016

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - TAMPA, FL

Insurance Carrier Onboarding Applications: Assisted in the development and maintenance of the company's healthcare dashboard applications used by the nation's largest health care providers. The application must meet HIPPA healthcare regulatory standards.

- Developed User Interface style guide based on best practices/principles to fulfill the needs of the wide range of users that could potentially use this application. Used Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Participated in User Experience discussions.
- Integrated new UI features using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript into dashboard application while adhering to HIPPA regulatory standards.
- Used git for version control
- Worked with RESTful APIs to consume data in JSON data format and display using JavaScript Objects etc.

Environment: ¡Query, RESTful API, JavaScript, Photoshop, Git, HTML5, CSS, Grunt, PHP

MDLIVE Inc.

JUL 2015 - APR 2016

FRONT END DEVELOPER - SUNRISE, FL

MDLIVE Client Landing Pages: An on-demand telehealth app that provided patients with remote access via video, phone, and secure email to board certified physicians. Major carriers who subscribe to the telehealth service gain access through customized landing page templates.

- Developed customized landing pages for healthcare vendors using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript with Ruby on Rails
- Assisted in developing and maintaining responsive web applications using the principles of UI/UX. Troubleshoot and fix bugs on front-end.
- Performed Usability Testing and bug fixes
- Managed JIRA task that pertains to each vendor
- Used git for version control

Environment: jQuery, RESTful API, JavaScript, Photoshop, Ruby on Rails, Git, Jira, CSS, HTML

ABILITY COMMERCE

SEPT 2014 - MAY 2015

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - DELRAY BEACH, FL

Marketing CMS: Maintained client websites improving the User Interface, Web Graphics, Content Style Guides, Wireframes and Prototypes for e-commerce platform.

- Maintained company's content management system for each specific vendor using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Designed product promotions and sales event flyers
- Designed HTML email marketing templates using HTML and CSS3.
- Developed low and high-fidelity mockup
- Participated in User Experience and User Interface Design discussions
- Used git for version control

Environment: jQuery, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop, C#, .NET

PORTFOLIO:

Github: https://www.github.com/abigby

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hireabigby

Website: Coming Soon